<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Hermes FTP Project</title>
        <author email="nospam.AT.larsbehnke.DOT.de">Lars Behnke</author>
    </properties>
    <meta name="keyword" content="ftp, java, spring, rfc959, hermes" />
    <body>
        <section name="Introduction">
            <subsection name="Overview">
                <p>
                    Hermes FTP Server is a free, cross-platform FTP server adhering to RFC 959, RFC 2228, RFC 2389, and RFC
                    2428. It is being developed in Java with a focus on security and extensibility. Currently, these
                    features are supported:
                    <ul>
                        <li>Active and passive transfer mode.</li>
                        <li>Customizable data channel ports (firewall friendly).</li>
                        <li>Block transmission mode and mainframe record structure.</li>
                        <li>ASCII, EBCDIC, and UTF-8 code pages.</li>
                        <li>Data encryption via 128-Bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL/TLS).</li>
                        <li>Authentication via implicit or explicit SSL/TLS.</li>
                        <li>Network protocols IPv4 and IPv6.</li>
                        <li>Data compression (MODE Z).</li>
                        <li>Pre-configured Windows service or Linux daemon.</li>
                        <li>Management of users and user groups via XML file.</li>
                        <li>Global and group based bandwidth limits.</li>
                        <li>Group based transfer volume limits</li>
                        <li>Group based authorization model.</li>
                        <li>User password encryption.</li>
                        <li>IP black lists.</li>
                        <li>Embedded web console for monitoring statistics, logs etc. via browser.</li>
                        <li>Per-user and per-session statistics.</li>
                        <li>Strong focus on extensibility and ability to integrate into different environments.</li>

                        <!-- <li>Upload/Download quota</li>
                            <li>Anti hammering feature</li>
                        -->
                    </ul>
                </p>
                <p>
                    Hermes FTP server is a console application, configured exclusively through XML files. An embedded web
                    console allows for monitoring resource consumption, session statistics, user statistics and log files.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Motivation">
                <p>
                    The development of yet another FTP server was driven by the motivation to provide a flexible, customizable
                    software that is able to integrate into various environments such as J2EE.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Apart from FTP specific settings, such as connection limits or supported cipher suites, the internal
                    structure of the application can be configured as well. The IoC based architecture allows for registering
                    new FTP commands or replacing existing ones without the need to recompile the Hermes FTP server application.
                    Hence, by re-implementing a subset of the FTP command classes, you could make Hermes FTP server behave like
                    an EJB client delegating requests directly to an application server instead of accessing the local file
                    system.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Hermes FTP Server is based on the
                    <a href="http://www.springframework.org/">Spring Framework</a>
                    . So, if you are familiar with this framework and its underlying concept of
                    <i>dependency injection</i>
                    you will get started quickly developing customized extensions.

                </p>
                <br />

            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Related Projects">
                <p>
                    Want to give another FTP server a try? Here is a list of similar OSS projects developed
                    in Java.
                </p>
                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <th>Name</th>
                        <th>Link</th>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Apache FTP Server</td>
                        <td>
                            <a href="http://incubator.apache.org/ftpserver">http://incubator.apache.org/ftpserver</a>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Anomic FTP Server</td>
                        <td>
                            <a href="http://www.anomic.de/AnomicFTPServer">http://www.anomic.de/AnomicFTPServer</a>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Cross FTP Server</td>
                        <td>
                            <a href="http://www.crossftp.com/crossftpserver.htm">http://www.crossftp.com/crossftpserver.htm</a>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>JFTPD</td>
                        <td>
                            <a href="http://www.ryanheise.com/software/jftpd">http://www.ryanheise.com/software/jftpd</a>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>edtFTPJ</td>
                        <td>
                            <a href="http://www.enterprisedt.com/products/edtftpj">
                                http://www.enterprisedt.com/products/edtftpj
                            </a>
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </table>
            </subsection>

        </section>
    </body>
</document>
